# **Shivam Bhasin**

Full Stack Android Developer

Experienced Web and Android Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the public policy industry. Skilled in Java, Android, Spring Boot, MySql, MongoDb, Flutter and Public Speaking. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology focused in Computer Science from Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, Noida.

## Skills —

### Overview



### **Programming**

 $0\ LOC \longrightarrow 5000\ LOC$ 

Java • Android • MySql

Python • Flutter(Dart) • MongoDB

C C++ • NodeJS • PostgreSql

### Contact



8130583124



shivamvk.github.io



16103223shivam@gmail.com



/in/shivam-bhasin-69a588158



shivamvk

### **Education**

2016 - 2020\* **BTech, Computer Science** (GPA: 6.4 / 10)

Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, Noida

2016 Intemediate, Science and Maths (CBSE score: 94.4 %)

St. Francis Convent School, Bareilly

### **Projects**

Job in tree Java Backend

Job search and recommendations by picking keywords from the resume uploaded as pdf and using machine learning.

- Created REST Api's for the project on Spring boot and MongoDb.
- · Also managed the AWS EC2 instance for database and server.
- Tools: Java, MongoDb, Spring, Android, Machine Learning, AWS
- Link: https://github.com/shivamvk/JobInTree-Server

Snipped Full Stack

A salon service booking app built with modern day UI/UX on flutter.

• Created the complete frontend on Coogle's latest mobile technol

- Created the complete frontend on Google's latest mobile technology Flutter.
- Created the backend with Spring Boot and MongoDb.
- Hosted the backend on AWS EC2 instance and also managed the database on the server.
- Tools: Java, Flutter, MongoDb, Spring, AWS
- Link: https://github.com/shivamvk/Snipped-Mobile
- Link: https://github.com/shivamvk/Snipped-Server

## **Experience**

Ju 2019 -Jul 2019

#### **Java Backend Developer**

Aedilics, Noida

- Made complete backend for Aedilics on Java using latest technologies like Spring Boot, Hibernate and MongoDB.
- Also took care of the AWS EC2 instance provided by the project lead.

Oct 2018 -Jan 2019

### **Google Code-in Mentor**

JBoss, RedHat

- Was a member of a team of 40 people selected from around the globe to mentor in Google code-in for JBoss, RedHat.
- We as a team created tasks for participants before the Google Codein started. After that we evaluated several submissions and also dealt with the participants' doubts.

Jul 2018 -Oct 2018

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Mindful Machine, Noida

 Created 3 android apps for Mindful Machine. The three apps included the customer app, shopkeeper's app and the admin app. Also managed the backend on firebase.

### **Extracurricular Activities**

#### Participated in JMUN'17

JIIT. Noida

Participated in Jaypee Model United Nations in the Lok Sabha committee.

### **Technical Coordinator**

Developer Student Clubs, JIIT Noida

Conducted a three day workshop on Google's latest technology for Mobile development, Flutter. The workshop was attended by an average of 50 students each day.